Guide to the Richard Hull Papers MC.260
New York University Archives
Richard Hull Papers
1968-2011
New York University Archives
Hull, Richard W., 1940-
MC.260
1 linear foot in one record carton
Richard W. Hull is a former Professor of History at New York University specializing in African history. Hull received his Ph.D. from Columbia University in 1968, and taught and published widely on subjects including African urbanization, segregation in South Africa, democratization in Africa, and Africa-Chinese relations. This collection consists of materials created and collected by Richard Hull documenting his involvement in academic policy and planning with the New York University Faculty Council and Senate. Materials include correspondence, photographs, membership lists, meeting minutes, memoranda, pamphlets, magazines, and reports from meetings of the Faculty Council. Topics present include student life, academic curriculum programming, proposals for new faculty positions, and the affirmative action committee activities.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of materials created and collected by Richard Hull documenting his involvement in academic policy and planning with the New York University Faculty Council and Senate. Materials include correspondence, photographs, membership lists, meeting minutes, memoranda, pamphlets, magazines, and reports from meetings of the Faculty Council. Topics present include student life, academic curriculum programming, proposals for new faculty positions, and the affirmative action committee activities.
Biographical Note
Richard W. Hull is a former Professor of History at New York University specializing in African history. Hull received his Ph.D. from Columbia University in 1968, and taught and published widely on subjects including African urbanization, segregation in South Africa, democratization in Africa, and Africa-Chinese relations. Hull has been the recipient of numerous awards including the United Nations Distinguished Citizen Award, NYU's Alumni Association Award for "Great Teacher," and a "Distinguished Africanist Award" by the New York African Studies Association.
Conditions Governing Access
Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. It is arranged in the order in which it was received from the donor.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Richard Hull in 2015. The accession number associated with this gift is 2016.008.
Curriculum planning.; Budget and Resource Planning.; Administrative records.; New York University -- Administration -- History; New York University -- Faculty -- History
- Faculty Council/Senate, Fall 1996 (Box 1)
- New York University Long-Range Plan; Interim Report of the University-Wide Planning Commission; Summary Reports of the Schools and Colleges, 1988 October (Box 1)
- Faculty Council, Fall 1989, Spring 1990 (Box 1)
- Faculty Council/Senate, Fall 1995 (Box 1)
- NYU Publications, 1981-1986 (Box 1)
- Faculty Council/Administration Issues, Fall 1996 (Box 1)
- Faculty Council Spring 1996 (Box 1)
- Faculty Council, Fall 1987, Spring 1988 (Box 1)
- Memorandum and Minutes, 1995 December (Box 1)
- Faculty Council, Spring 1989 (Box 1)
- Student Life, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
- University/Department, 1975 (Box 1)
- Morse Academic Plan Handbook and Newsletter, 2010-2011 (Box 1)
- NYU Faculty Council, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
- NYU Senate, 1982-1988 (Box 1)
- Senate, Spring 1989 (Box 1)
- Faculty Council, Spring 1997 (Box 1)
- Policy and Planning, Autumn 1979 (Box 1)
- Affirmative Action Committee, Fall 1996 (Box 1)
- Publications and Correspondence, 1995-2006 (Box 1)
- Faculty Council Administration Issues, Spring 1989 (Box 1)
- Report on Admissions: The September 1979 Class, 1980 (Box 1)
- Faculty Council/Senate, Fall 1997 (Box 1)
- UG Curriculum Committee: UG Reform, circa 1970-1990 (Box 1)
- Commission on the Effective Use of University Resources, 1970 (Box 1)
- Faculty Council Administration Issues, Fall 1988, Spring 1989 (Box 1)
- Faculty Senate, Fall 1989, Spring 1990 (Box 1)
- Faculty Council/Senate, Fall 1988 (Box 1)
- NYU Charter and Bylaws, 1968 (Box 1)
- Humanistic Perspectives on Foreign Cultures, 1983 (Box 1)